# Corey Sabia

**Phone** +1 (203) 451-5785

Email corey@coreysabia.com

**Address** 473 Thayer Pond Road

Wilton, CT 06897

**Web** sabia.tech

# **Intrests and Summary**

Information Security, Cyber Security and Computer Information System; this has stemmed from hands on work and research.

General interests span a wide variety of topics. Continuous learning on a variety of subjects is critical, and always leads to new challenges and increases the development of knowledge. This mindset alows me to evolve and grow professionally and personally.

# **Professional Experience**

Technology Security Intern - Bridgewater Associates, LP, Westport, CT

Summer 2018 - Present

#### System Administrator Intern - Wilton Public Schools, Wilton, CT

2016 - Present

Coordinate and implement district-wide technology upgrades. Work with Network Administrator on day to day management and maintenance of network infrastructure. Researched and then implemented innovative technology programs and software to solve system design flaws and shortcomings, to meet the high demands of the district. Management of over three thousand student and staff devices. Assisted in designing and implementing the Ready Access Digital Learning Program, a technology-in-education curriculum for incorporating and supporting technology use in and out of the classroom, for the start of the 2017-18 school year.

Media Program Director - Wilton Public Schools

2015 - Present

Manage and improve recently created TV/Media Studios at each school. Propose and write public and private grants, manage funds and purchase equipment to continuously develop each schools' respective program. Coordinate with over twenty school administrators and staff to develop programs geared around content creation at every grade level.

Founded and continue to develop the current WETV (Wilton Educational TV) program, which offers students at the high school level an opportunity to videotape, manage and distribute the district's video content related to Board of Education meetings and other district based events.

Sailing Instructor - Roton Point Association, Norwalk, CT

Summer 2017

Created and organized detailed weekly lesson plans to help coach both adult and child sailors efficiently. Helped sailors develop their sailboat handling techniques and racing tactics.

Assistant to Sailing Director - Norwalk Yacht Club, Norwalk, CT

2013-16

Maintained a fleet of sailboats and motorboats. Helped organize and run weekly internal club races. Assisted in the general management of Junior Sailing Program.

# Volunteer and Leadership Experience

## Digital Advisory Council Member - Wilton Board of Education, Wilton, CT

2017-Present

Invited onboard Wilton Board of Education Digital Advisory Council which was put into effect to help guide and develop the ongoing effort to provide ideal technology support for student education.

## Morning Warrior Club President - Wilton High School, Wilton, CT

2016-17

Led a group of over thirty students to produce a weekly student news broadcast which incorporated and discussed relevant news from students, the community and around the world. Redefined how the weekly broadcasts were carried out, and created a system of cooperative idea making followed by active implementation for students involved to effectively create their content.

## Apprentice and Mentor - Ambler Farm, Wilton, CT

2009-17

Learned to take care of animals, gardens and upkeep the property as an apprentice before becoming a mentor who lead and taught over a hundred apprentices; and soon took on a larger roll of aiding in the daily management and operations of the farm including leading community programs, maintaining and operating heavy equipment, as well as carrying out carpentry and construction work to improve the overall look, feel and functionality of the farm.

### Peer Mediator - Wilton High School

2016-17

Worked with school administrators to alleviate their work flow from student conflict matters and allow them to spend time on more important matters. Professionally trained in conflict resolution to facilitate discussion among peers, and guide students to reach their own solutions.

# Education

Roger Williams University - Expected Graduation May 2021 BS in Cyber Security & Networking Minor in Computer Science

Wilton High School - Class of 2017

## **Awards**

Wilton High School American Citizenship Award - 2017
Recognizes seniors who participate in school and community

service, show a positive attitude, possess strength of character and promote citizenship through school and community activities.

Wilton High School PTSA Library Learning Commons Award - 2017
Presented to seniors who have demonstrated the highest
quality of performance in specific subject areas.

Presidential Service Award - 2017 Awarded for over 250 volunteer hours within a year.

Ambler Farm Betty Ambler Award - 2017 Awarded for years of volunteer service work on the farm.

Norwalk Yacht Club Seamanship Award - 2010/2013/2015 Norwalk Yacht Club Commodore's Cup - 2014